<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Ryshe Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://ryansheehan.github.io/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 21:48:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Launching the Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[MotivationStarting my own personal site has been on my todo list for quite some time. Not
only have I been a professional software engineer…]]></description><link>https://ryansheehan.github.io//launching-the-blog/launching-the-blog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ryansheehan.github.io//launching-the-blog/launching-the-blog/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 23:46:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting my own personal site has been on my todo list for quite some time. Not
only have I been a professional software engineer for over 10 years, but I have
spent some time as a professional scrum master.  Over the years I have
accumulated many hard earned lessons that I think are worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do I wish to share my thoughts, but I believe writing is the next
appropriate step in my career.  Leadership is something I have always been
interested, and for a while now, my career has straddled this line between
software engineering and software development leadership.  To keep pushing my
career forward, I need present my thoughts and ideas to larger audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I like to tinker with code!  A personal site would serve as an
excellent portfolio to any little side projects I put together; including this
site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always a little scary to put your ideas out to the world for criticism, but
I believe it is in discourse that great ideas rise to the top.  Arguably, one of
my best qualities is being forthcoming with opinions.  I believe that having to
justify your ideas to those both smarter than yourself, and to those that are
inexperienced and naive, is a great way to solidify and revalidate your
opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fear is not being able to keep up with writing.  Time is a commodity
that is not bountiful for me.  I expect to fall off the wagon with regular
writing, but it’s important to keep returning to writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last fear is about maintenance.  Should I be able to write regularly there is
the potential the old ideas will not get updated.  My thoughts and ideas evolve,
and I wouldn’t want outdated thoughts to define this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep the motivation for writing, I believe I’ll need to maintain a
topic list.  That way when it comes time to write, I don’t have to first think
about a topic.  If I am not writing about a topic, I plan to journal progress on
any ongoing side projects.  My initial goal is to write one post per month.
Being regular will be critical to forming my writing habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I expect, my posts will be about getting this site up and running.
Documenting my thoughts about managing development projects, on a professional
level, will quickly follow.  I expect a bumpy ride to start, but I’m looking
forward to building up this site!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>